$CONSTELLATION	CONSTELLATION
$CHARACTER	CHARACTER
$FACTIONS	FACTIONS
$STATS	STATS
$DETAIL_BUTTON_SHOW	Show Details
$DETAIL_BUTTON_HIDE	Hide Details
$OPEN_SKILLS_MENU	Open Skills Menu
$CHANGE_PLAYER_TITLE	Change Title
$SPEC	SPECIALIZATION
$TITLE_CONNECTOR	of the
$NO_FACTION	No faction yet
$UNIT_TIME	pts/s
$POINTS	pts

$HEAL_RATE	Health Regen
$MAGICKA_RATE	Magicka Regen
$STAMINA_RATE	Stamina Regen
$SPEED	Movement Speed
$WEAPON_SPEED	Weapon Speed
$MAGIC_RESIST	Magic Resistance
$FIRE_RESIST	Fire Resistance
$FROST_RESIST	Frost Resistance
$SHOCK_RESIST	Shock Resistance
$POISON_RESIST	Poison Resistance
$DISEASE_RESIST	Disease Resistance
$RIGHT_HAND_POISE	Right Hand Poise Damage
$LEFT_HAND_POISE	Left Hand Poise Damage
$POISE_ARMOR_RESIST	Physical Poise Resistance
$POISE_MAGIC_RESIST	Magic Poise Resistance
$ARMOR_DAMAGE_MITIGATION	Physical Damage Reduction
$CRIT_CHANCE	Critical Strike Chance
$CRIT_DAMAGE	Critical Strike Damage
$RIGHT_HAND_DAMAGE	Right Hand Damage
$LEFT_HAND_DAMAGE	Left Hand Damage

$Acrobat	Acrobat
$Agent	Agent
$Archer	Archer
$Assassin	Assassin
$Barbarian	Barbarian
$Bard	Bard
$Battlemage	Battlemage
$Crusader	Crusader
$Healer	Healer
$Knight	Knight
$Mage	Mage
$Monk	Monk
$Nightblade	Nightblade
$Pilgrim	Pilgrim
$Rogue	Rogue
$Scout	Scout
$Sorcerer	Sorcerer
$Spellsword	Spellsword
$Thief	Thief
$Warrior	Warrior
$Witchhunter	Witchhunter

$Doomstone_Warrior	The Warrior
$Doomstone_Mage	The Mage
$Doomstone_Thief	The Thief
$Doomstone_Lover	The Lover
$Doomstone_Lord	The Lord
$Doomstone_Lady	The Lady
$Doomstone_Steed	The Steed
$Doomstone_Apprentice	The Apprentice
$Doomstone_Atronach	The Atronach
$Doomstone_Ritual	The Ritual
$Doomstone_Shadow	The Shadow
$Doomstone_Tower	The Tower
$Doomstone_Serpent	The Serpent

$Stealth	Stealth
$Combat	Combat
$Magic	Magic

$Acrobat_Description	The kind of person that uses agility and endurance to their advantage. Unafraid of jumping long distances.
$Agent_Description	Charming when they can be seen, and nearly invisible when in shadow.
$Archer_Description	A marksman, adept at combat at great distances. Able to take down most foes before they have a chance to draw sword.
$Assassin_Description	Nimble and quiet, they move in darkness to strike at the unsuspecting. Locks hold no doors shut for them.
$Barbarian_Description	Fearsome brutes who inspire fear and dread in the hearts of their enemies. Like a storm, swift and powerful. Finding little use for heavy armor, they rely on smashing their foes into the ground.
$Bard_Description	Intelligent and personable, they prefer to accomplish tasks with their words first, and sword second.
$Battlemage_Description	Able to resolve most conflicts with either spell or sword. They are a deadly mix of scholar and soldier.
$Crusader_Description	A combatant who wields the power of brute strength and medicinal knowledge. Cheating death after every fight, they rely on their keen knowledge of restoration to fight yet again.
$Healer_Description	Fighters of poison and illness. The ancient art of restoration is their ally, and the deadly art of destruction is their weapon.
$Knight_Description	The most noble of all combatants. Strong in body and in character.
$Mage_Description	Prefering to use their extensive knowledge of all things magical, they wield a might more powerful than the sharpest blade.
$Monk_Description	Quick and cunning with the empty hand, they are strong in spirit. They prefer to solve conflict by arrow or by fist.
$Nightblade_Description	Spell and shadow are their friends. By darkness they move with haste, casting magic to benefit their circumstances.
$Pilgrim_Description	Hearty folk, well-versed in the tomes of old. They profit in life by bartering in the market, or by persuading the weak-minded.
$Rogue_Description	They use speed in combat rather than brute force. Persuasive in conversation, their tongues are as sharp as blades.
$Scout_Description	Preferring the rolling countryside to the city life, they are gifted with the ability to evade, guard, and protect themselves with great proficiency.
$Sorcerer_Description	Besting the most well-equipped fighters, they rely on the spells of the mystic arts. Unique to these mages is the bodily stamina to be armed with the thickest armor.
$Spellsword_Description	More nimble and athletic than the sorcerer, and better suited for spell-casting than the knight, their attacks are unpredictable. Students of combat and magic.
$Thief_Description	Profiting from the losses of others is their love. Able to be swift in shadow, and crafty in bartering. Locks are enemies, and lock-picks are their swords.
$Warrior_Description	Unafraid of light weaponry, they plow into the fray with little regard for injury. Masters of all melee tools, they put little faith in the magical arts.
$Witchhunter_Description	Swift on foot, and clever with spells, they use distance as their ally. Slower adversaries are fodder for their arrows.

$Apprentice_Agent_Description	Charming when they wish to be seen, and nearly invisible when they do not, agents are skilled in the arts of subterfuge and deception. When threatened, agents strike from afar with arrows coated in deadly poison. As an agent, your poisons last for 50% extra hits.
$Apprentice_Archer_Description	A marksman who strikes from a distance, taking down foes before they even draw a weapon. As an archer, you move 20% faster while drawing your bow.
$Apprentice_Assassin_Description	Swift and deadly, assassins move through shadows to strike at unsuspecting foes. Their short blades are whetted with the blood of previous kills. As an assassin, you deal 25% extra damage with sneak attacks.
$Apprentice_Barbarian_Description	Fearsome warriors who wield Two-handed weapons to inspire fear in the hearts of their enemies. As a barbarian, your power attacks deal 50% extra attack of opportunity damage.
$Apprentice_Battlemage_Description	Protected by heavy armor and armed with Destruction magic, battlemages are a deadly mix of scholar and soldier. As a battlemage, your wards resist 50% of incoming weapon damage.
$Apprentice_Crusader_Description	Heavily armored warriors who use their shields and their keen knowledge of Restoration to rid the world of evil. As a crusader, you resist 50% of incoming arrow and spell damage when you block with a shield.
$Apprentice_Healer_Description	Healers do battle against injury, poison, and disease. The ancient art of Restoration is their ally, and also their weapon. As a healer, your Restoration spells cost 20% less when dual cast.
$Apprentice_Knight_Description	Knights are students of the noble arts of war. In addition to their schooling in letters and speechcraft, knights also learn to care for their arms and armor on the battlefield. As a knight, you resist 10% of all incoming weapon and spell damage.
$Apprentice_Mage_Description	Relying on their extensive knowledge of Alteration magic for protection, mages wield a power more deadly than even the sharpest blade. As a mage, your Magicka Regeneration is increased by 50%.
$Apprentice_Monk_Description	Monks combine the martial and mystic arts, protecting themselves with spells while engaging foes in hand-to-hand combat. As a monk, your Armor Rating is increased by 100 while unarmed.
$Apprentice_Nightblade_Description	Spell and shadow are the nightblade’s friend. Their affinity for Illusion magic gives them a sinister reputation. As a nightblade, your Illusion spells are twice as strong while you are undetected.
$Apprentice_Rogue_Description	Rogues are adventurers and opportunists with a gift for talking themselves out of trouble. When threatened, a rogue’s tongue is as sharp as their blade. As a rogue, you deal 25% extra power attack damage while you have an empty offhand.
$Apprentice_Scout_Description	Cautious warriors who rely on speed and cunning, scouts use bows to fight from range, and shields to protect themselves when the fight comes to them. As a scout, your Stamina Regeneration is increased by 50%.
$Apprentice_Sorcerer_Description	Spellcasters who rely on enchantments and summoned servants for protection. Their desire for power often leads where others refuse to go. As a sorcerer, you have a 10% chance to absorb the Magicka from incoming spells.
$Apprentice_Spellsword_Description	Warriors trained in the art of magic, spellswords wield both blade and spell. Their skill with One-handed weapons makes them deadly at close range. As a spellsword, Destruction spells cost 20% less while you have a weapon equipped.
$Apprentice_Thief_Description	Thieves are pickpockets and pilferers who profit from the loss of others. Unlike common bandits, thieves prefer subterfuge over violence. As a thief, you move 20% faster while sneaking.
$Apprentice_Warrior_Description	Warriors are professional fighters who plow into the fray with little regard for danger. Adept with all weapons, warriors rely on heavy armor to protect them in battle. As a warrior, your Health Regeneration is increased by 50%.
$Apprentice_Witchhunter_Description	Witchhunters are dedicated to rooting out and destroying the evil practices of dark cults and profane sorcery. They do battle with Conjuration magic and potent elixirs. As a witchhunter, your potions last 50% longer.

$Apprentice_Acrobatic_Description	You jump twice as high and take 50% less damage from falling.
$Apprentice_Arcane_Description	Your spells and enchantments cost 20% less, but you cannot regenerate Magicka in combat.
$Apprentice_Athletic_Description	Sprinting costs 50% less Stamina.
$Apprentice_Blessed_Description	Healing scrolls are twice as strong, and you have a small chance to find healing scrolls on fallen enemies.
$Apprentice_Brutal_Description	You deal 10% extra damage with weapons, but you move 10% slower.
$Apprentice_Cannibal_Description	You have a small chance to find human flesh and human hearts when killing humanoids.
$Apprentice_Careful_Description	You take 25% less damage from attacks of opportunity, but you deal 25% less attack of opportunity damage to enemies.
$Apprentice_Charming_Description	Your buying and selling prices are improved by 10%, and you have the power to calm your enemies.
$Apprentice_Craven_Description	You move 10% faster, but take 10% extra weapon and spell damage.
$Apprentice_Cursed_Description	Your reanimation spells cost 50% less, but healing spells cost twice as much.
$Apprentice_Disciplined_Description	You gain 20% extra experience in class skills, but 20% less experience in all other skills.
$Apprentice_Drunkard_Description	Alcohol is twice as strong, but when you are not under the effect of alcohol, your Magicka and Stamina are reduced by 50.
$Apprentice_Elusive_Description	You have the power to vanish into the shadows.
$Apprentice_Faithful_Description	Divine amulets are twice as strong.
$Apprentice_Faithless_Description	You cannot benefit from shrines.
$Apprentice_Favored_Description	You have the power to summon a Guardian Spirit.
$Apprentice_Foolhardy_Description	Your armor is more effective when you are not wearing a helmet.
$Apprentice_Gifted_Description	You do not benefit from your class's starting skills.
$Apprentice_Hearty_Description	Your Disease Resistance is increased by 50%.
$Apprentice_Hoarder_Description	Your Carry Weight is increased by 100, but your selling prices are reduced by 20%.
$Apprentice_Intimidating_Description	You are much more likely to succeed at intimidation checks, and you have the power to send enemies fleeing in fear.
$Apprentice_Milkdrinker_Description	Bonuses from milk are five times stronger, and you find extra milk in your travels.
$Apprentice_Mundane_Description	You resist 20% of incoming spell damage, but your spells and enchantments cost five times as much.
$Apprentice_Prepared_Description	Your Carry Weight is increased by 25, and you find extra cooking ingredients in your travels.
$Apprentice_Reckless_Description	You deal 25% extra damage to staggered targets, but take 25% extra damage while staggered.
$Apprentice_Rugged_Description	Your Injury Resistance is increased by 50%.
$Apprentice_Stormborn_Description	Your Shock Resistance is increased by 50%.
$Apprentice_SweetTooth_Description	You have a small chance to find Skooma on fallen enemies.
$Apprentice_Trollkin_Description	Your Health Regeneration is increased by 100%, but your Fire Resistance is reduced by 50%.
$Apprentice_Venomous_Description	You have a chance to find poisons on slain enemies.
$Apprentice_Versatile_Description	You no longer benefit from your racial passive, but your Health, Magicka, and Stamina are increased by 25.
$Apprentice_Wanted_Description	You receive 20% better prices with fences.

$Acrobatic	Acrobatic
$Arcane	Arcane
$Athletic	Athletic
$Blessed	Blessed
$Brutal	Brutal
$Cannibal	Cannibal
$Careful	Careful
$Charming	Charming
$Craven	Craven
$Cursed	Cursed
$Disciplined	Disciplined
$Drunkard	Drunkard
$Elusive	Elusive
$Faithful	Faithful
$Faithless	Faithless
$Favored	Favored
$Foolhardy	Foolhardy
$Gifted	Gifted
$Hearty	Hearty
$Hoarder	Hoarder
$Intimidating	Intimidating
$Milkdrinker	Milkdrinker
$Mundane	Mundane
$Prepared	Prepared
$Reckless	Reckless
$Rugged	Rugged
$Stormborn	Stormborn
$Sweet Tooth	Sweet Tooth
$Trollkin	Trollkin
$Venomous	Venomous
$Versatile	Versatile
$Wanted	Wanted

$COMPANIONS	Companions
$COHORT	Cohort
$COMPANION	Companion
$SHIELD_BROTHER	Shield-Brother
$SHIELD_SISTER	Shield-Sister
$HARBINGER	Harbinger

$THIEVES	Thieves' Guild
$AGENT	Agent
$GUILD_MASTER	Guild Master
$NIGHTINGALES	Nightingales

$COLLEGE_WH	College of Winterhold
$STUDENT	Student
$SCHOLAR	Scholar
$WIZARD	Wizard
$MASTER-WIZARD	Master-Wizard
$ARCHMAGE	Arch-Mage

$DARK_BROTHERHOOD	Dark Brotherhood
$APPRENTICE	Apprentice
$ASSASSIN	Assassin
$SILENCER	Silencer
$LISTENER	Listener

$EMPIRE	Imperial Legion
$AUXILIARY	Auxiliary
$QUAESTOR	Quaestor
$PRAEFECT	Praefect
$TRIBUNE	Tribune
$LEGATE	Legate

$STORMCLOAKS	Stormcloaks
$UNBLOODED	Unblooded
$ICE_VEINS	Ice-Veins
$BONE_BREAKER	Bone-Breaker
$SNOW_HAMMER	Snow-Hammer
$STORMBLADE	Stormblade

$GREYBEARDS	Greybeards
$DRAGONBORN	Dragonborn
$YSMIR	Ysmir

$BARDS_COLLEGE	Bards College
$BARD	Bard
$ARCHBARD	Archbard

$DAWNGUARD	Dawnguard
$HUNTER	Hunter
$HUNTRESS	Huntress
$PALADIN	Paladin

$VOLKIHAR	Volkihar Clan
$COURTIER	Courtier
$COURTIERESS	Courtieress
$LORD	Lord
$LADY	Lady

$PENITUS	Penitus Oculatus

$TELVANNI	House Telvanni
$HONOR_MEMBER	Honorary Member

$CLASS	CLASS
$TRAIT	TRAIT

$Paradigm_Sentinel	Sentinel
$Paradigm_Merchant	Merchant
$Paradigm_Ranger	Ranger
$Paradigm_Assassin	Assassin
$Paradigm_Barbarian	Barbarian
$Paradigm_Bard	Bard
$Paradigm_Reaver	Reaver
$Paradigm_TavernBrawler	Tavern Brawler
$Paradigm_Crusader	Crusader
$Paradigm_Spellsword	Spellsword
$Paradigm_WitchDoctor	Witch Doctor
$Paradigm_Arcanist	Arcanist
$Paradigm_Artisan	Artisan
$Paradigm_Cleric	Cleric
$Paradigm_Knight	Knight
$Paradigm_Beggar	Beggar
$Paradigm_Monk	Monk
$Paradigm_Duelist	Duelist
$Paradigm_Nightblade	Nightblade
$Paradigm_Berserker	Berserker
$Paradigm_Scout	Scout
$Paradigm_Shaman	Shaman
$Paradigm_Sorcerer	Sorcerer
$Paradigm_Battlemage	Battlemage
$Paradigm_Warlock	Warlock
$Paradigm_Thief	Thief
$Paradigm_Warrior	Warrior
$Paradigm_Witchhunter	Witchhunter

$Paradigm_Sentinel_Description	Masters of the defensive arts, sentinels combine heavy armor and marksman skills to hold their ground against overwhelming odds. Their disciplined stance allows them to build offensive and defensive momentum while remaining firmly planted.
$Paradigm_Merchant_Description	Skilled traders and craftsmen, merchants rely on speech and smithing to turn their expertise into profit. Their mastery of commerce allows them to carry more and secure better prices from their dealings.
$Paradigm_Ranger_Description	Mobile hunters who excel at striking from range, rangers combine marksmanship with light armor and stealth. They are most dangerous when keeping their enemies at a distance.
$Paradigm_Assassin_Description	Nimble and deadly, assassins strike from the shadows with poisoned blades. Their mastery of stealth and one-handed weapons makes them particularly lethal when attacking from behind.
$Paradigm_Barbarian_Description	Fierce warriors who rely on strength, speed, and two-handed weapons rather than heavy armor. Barbarians overwhelm their enemies with crushing blows while remaining difficult to stagger.
$Paradigm_Bard_Description	Charismatic performers who combine speechcraft and Illusion magic to inspire allies and manipulate enemies. Their songs and spells become more powerful through their mastery of performance.
$Paradigm_Reaver_Description	Dark warriors who bind supernatural weapons to their service. Reavers combine one-handed combat with Conjuration magic, using bound weapons to rend both body and soul.
$Paradigm_TavernBrawler_Description	Fighters who have mastered the art of unarmed combat. Tavern brawlers turn their fists into deadly weapons, building momentum through repeated strikes and using their guard to withstand punishment.
$Paradigm_Crusader_Description	Holy warriors who combine two-handed weapons with the power of Restoration. Crusaders bring divine retribution to their enemies while using restorative magic to sustain themselves in battle.
$Paradigm_Spellsword_Description	Warriors trained equally in the blade and the arcane arts. Spellswords flow between melee combat and destructive magic, empowering each through the other.
$Paradigm_WitchDoctor_Description	Masters of alchemy and Restoration who use poisons to weaken their enemies. Witch doctors specialize in turning toxic mixtures and restorative magic into devastating tools of combat.
$Paradigm_Arcanist_Description	Scholars of destructive and protective magic who manipulate the flow of arcane power. Arcanists conserve magical energy through repeated casting before unleashing powerful spells.
$Paradigm_Artisan_Description	Master craftsmen who combine Enchanting and Smithing to create exceptional equipment. Artisans sacrifice raw enchantment strength for versatility while perfecting the weapons and armor they create.
$Paradigm_Cleric_Description	Devout warriors who combine Restoration magic with heavy armor. Clerics strengthen their blessings through combat, creating powerful defensive protections and divine effects that sustain them in battle.
$Paradigm_Knight_Description	Disciplined warriors who rely on shields and heavy armor to withstand their enemies. Knights build momentum through successful blocks, becoming increasingly powerful and resilient as the battle continues.
$Paradigm_Beggar_Description	The humblest of adventurers, beggars begin their journey with almost nothing. Though they lack the advantages of other classes, those chosen by fate gain unusual strength against dragons and their servants.
$Paradigm_Monk_Description	Disciplined martial artists who combine unarmed combat with Alteration magic. Monks use precise strikes and mystical defenses to overcome their enemies without relying on conventional weapons.
$Paradigm_Duelist_Description	Swift and precise warriors who specialize in one-handed combat and defense. Duelists thrive on timing, turning successful attacks, blocks, and evasions into momentum that keeps their opponents under pressure.
$Paradigm_Nightblade_Description	Assassins of the arcane arts who combine stealth with Illusion magic. Nightblades manipulate perception from the shadows, striking their enemies before they realize they are in danger.
$Paradigm_Berserker_Description	Frenzied warriors who fight with two weapons and refuse to give their enemies an opening. Berserkers become more dangerous as they endure punishment, converting pain and aggression into devastating attacks.
$Paradigm_Scout_Description	Cautious hunters who rely on stealth and marksmanship to control the battlefield. Scouts move quickly through the wilderness and specialize in devastating attacks from concealment.
$Paradigm_Shaman_Description	Spiritual warriors who command summoned creatures and wield restorative magic. Shamans draw strength from their spirits, empowering themselves according to the nature of the creatures they call upon.
$Paradigm_Sorcerer_Description	Mystical spellcasters who rely on enchanted equipment, staffs, scrolls, and magical robes. Sorcerers use their knowledge of Alteration and Enchanting to amplify the power and duration of their magic.
$Paradigm_Battlemage_Description	Heavily armored spellcasters who combine Alteration magic with destructive spells. Battlemages turn their defenses into weapons, becoming stronger and more resilient as they endure magical and physical attacks.
$Paradigm_Warlock_Description	Dark practitioners who bind undead and Daedric servants to their will. Warlocks manipulate fear and summon supernatural allies, growing stronger as their enemies succumb to terror.
$Paradigm_Thief_Description	Swift and cunning criminals who rely on stealth and nimble hands rather than brute force. Thieves excel at infiltration, using their speed and skill to bypass locks and relieve others of their possessions.
$Paradigm_Warrior_Description	Professional fighters who rely on heavy armor and two-handed weapons to dominate the battlefield. Warriors build momentum through relentless power attacks, trading stamina for overwhelming force.
$Paradigm_Witchhunter_Description	Dedicated hunters of supernatural threats who combine alchemy, heavy weapons, and marksmanship. Witch hunters prepare themselves with potent mixtures before bringing silvered weapons to bear against creatures and undead.